

Muhammad Nouman Khan

Email: jammuhammadnoumankhan@gmail.com 📞 Phone: (+92) 03139520997

Website: https://github.com/iammuhammadnoumankhan

(C) WhatsApp Messenger: +923139520997

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/muhammad-nouman-khan-248530233

Gender: Male **Date of birth:** 20/06/2004 **Nationality:** Pakistani

ABOUT ME

I am a final-year student pursuing a Bachelor's in Artificial Intelligence at the Pak-Austria Fachhochschule Institute of Applied Sciences and Technology. With 3 years of experience as an AI engineer, I have worked on Machine Learning, Deep Learning, and Computer Vision projects. Currently, my focus is on Language Models, and I am adaptable to new technologies while actively engaging in research projects.

WORK EXPERIENCE

[01/07/2024 – Current]

GenAl Intern

Sybrid

City: Islamabad | **Country:** Pakistan

- Working on Generative AI specifically on Diffuser Models.
- Working on a Project related to Local demographics.

[10/10/2023 - 11/04/2024] **Database development engineer**

Canada Tax & Financial Services

City: Edmonton | Country: Canada

- · Database Management
- Automation
- Chatbot Creation

[28/08/2023 - 28/09/2023] **Summer Intern**

Rapidev

City: Islamabad | Country: Pakistan

ML/Computer Vision Intern

- Data Annotation utilizing CVAT and Roboflow
- · Managing GIS and raster data
- Crafting APIs for raster-to-vector conversion
- Model for Car number plate detection

[18/07/2022 - 25/09/2022] **Internship**

SPCAI - PAF-IAST

City: Haripur | Country: Pakistan

Machine Learning on Edge Devices

- Learn Python | Machine Learning & Deep Learning | Version Control | tflite
- Worked on OAK-D | Raspberry Pi
- Projects: Facial Attendance Management System | Solar Ir-radiance Fore-casting

EDUCATION AND TRAIN-ING

Bachelor of Applied Science and Information Technology, Artificial

Pak Austria Fachhochschule https://paf-iast.edu.pk/

Address: Khanpur road, Mang, 22620, Haripur, Pakistan

[05/08/2019 - 20/09/2021]

Intermediate

Pakistan Scouts Cadet College Batrasi https://www.pscc.edu.pk/

Address: Atarsheehsa, balakot road, 21300, Mansehra, Pakistan

[05/05/2017 – 27/06/2019]

Matric

Aurakzai Model School https://www.facebook.com/amsac.official/

Address: Hazara University,, 21300, Mansehra, Pakistan

PROJECTS

Facial Attendance Management System

I worked on a project called 'Facial Attendance Management System' using edge devices like OAK-D and Raspberry Pi. The model achieved over 95% accuracy in recognizing individuals. It also allowed for quick registration of new individuals by capturing their facial features within seconds and storing them in a database for future recognition.

Solar Irradiance Forecasting

I completed a project on solar irradiance forecasting under the supervision of Dr. Sohail. In this project, I obtained data from Stanford University and trained a forecasting model. This project was part of a smart building system initiative.

Fine Tune Whisper on Quranic Data (HuggingFace)

I fine-tuned a Whisper model from OpenAI on a custom dataset of Quranic recitations. After fine-tuning, the model is capable of transcribing Quranic audio into text.

Link: https://huggingface.co/iammuhammadnoumankhan/whisper-small-ar

Car Number Plate detection (YOLO)

I collected and scraped car images with prominent number plates and annotated them using RoboFlow. I then fine-tuned YOLOv8 for car number plate detection. After that, I integrated OCR (EasyOCR and Tesseract) to recognize the numbers and stored the data in a database.

Chatbot for Tax & Finance Services

I worked for a Canadian company (Tax & Finance Services) where I created a database and developed a chatbot for tax and finance services using OpenAI and Langchain.

Data Scrapers & Automation

I developed numerous web scrapers using Selenium, BeautifulSoup, and Requests for various tasks. I also worked on web automation projects, some for learning purposes and others for clients.

Attention based Glaucoma Detection

I worked on an already-published paper focused on attention-based glaucoma detection. I implemented the code for the paper, which used glaucoma images and incorporated an attention mechanism with a Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) in the detection model.

[01/03/2024 - 01/04/2024] **App Feedback Analyzer**

I worked on an Al-based project that takes a link to an app from the Play Store, scrapes the app's reviews, and analyzes them. It performs sentiment analysis to identify positive and negative feedback, provides suggestions for improvement, and highlights functional and non-functional requirements. In the end, the project generates a well-formatted report that includes all this information and visual charts.

Inventory Management System

I developed an 'Inventory Management System' project where I collected images of products on shelves from multiple stores. A friend annotated these images using RoboFlow, and I fine-tuned YOLOv8 on the dataset. The model was able to perform realtime multiple-object detection in store shelves.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Knowledge:

Data Science, Machine Learning, Deep, NLP & CV, LLMs, GPT

Languages:

Python, Matlab, HTML, CSS, Web development, SQL, NoSQL, MongoDB

Frameworks:

Tensorflow, Pytorch, Keras, Langchain, Crew AI, Django, Flask, Fast API, Llama index, Ollama

Cloud:

GCP Cloud Run, Amazon Sage Maker(AWS), Heroku

Libraries:

Numpy, Pandas, Sklearn, Spacy, NLTK, Opency, Matplotlib / Seaborn, scipy, Transformers, BeautifulSoup, Selenium

Tools:

Jupyter, docker, GitHub, Git, Google DataStudio, Gradio, Streamlit, Vscode, Kafka

Others:

Statistics & Probability, Calculus, Mathematics, Linear Algebra, Worked on Complex Datasets, Big data, Statistical Analysis, Data Mining, Model Building and Deploying, Hypothesis Testing, Data Analytics, Model Fine-tuning

PROJECTS EXHIBITION

[12/02/2023 - 12/02/2023]

Uraan Projects Exhibition(2023)

I secured the 4th position in the Uraan Project Exhibition on February 12, 2023, at Pak Austria Fachhochschule.

My Project was about "SOLAR IRRADIANCE FORECASTING".

Link: https://www.instagram.com/p/CojswxOgUDm/?igshid=MzRIODBiNWFIZA==

[07/07/2023 - 07/07/2023] Uraan Projects Exhibition (SPRING - 2023)

I secured the first position in the Uraan Project Exhibition on July 7, 2023, at Pak Austria Fachhochschule.

My project in the DJANGO FRAMEWORK was titled "WEB SITE WITH DIFFERENT AI MODELS DEPLOYED."

Link: https://www.linkedin.com/posts/muhammad-nouman-khan-248530233_ai-pythontechnology-activity-7083500779998765056-FS8Z?

utm source=share&utm medium=member android

CERTIFICATES & COURSES

Machine Learning Specilization (Deeplearning.ai)

Generative AI with Large Language Models (Deeplearning.ai)

SOFT SKILLS

Skills

- Analytical Thinking
- · Problem-Solving
- Collaboration
- Communication
- Continuous Learning
- Adaptability
- Time Management

Spoken Languages

- English
- Urdu

Thank you for taking the time to review my CV. I am excited about the opportunity to contribute my skills and experience to your organization. I am a dedicated and hardworking individual who is committed to achieving success and making a positive impact in my work. I am confident that my qualifications make me a strong candidate. Thank you for your consideration, and I look forward to hearing from you soon.

Muhammad Nouman

Khan